<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Markdown | My Site</title>
    <link>https://nvgaforov.github.io/en/tags/markdown/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://nvgaforov.github.io/en/tags/markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Markdown</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://nvgaforov.github.io/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Markdown</title>
      <link>https://nvgaforov.github.io/en/tags/markdown/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Week</title>
      <link>https://nvgaforov.github.io/en/post/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nvgaforov.github.io/en/post/11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week, as a computer science student, I experienced a series of interesting and eventful moments. Monday started with a lecture on graph theory, where we studied search and optimization algorithms for graphs. In the evening, I spent time finishing a Java lab, implementing data processing algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday and Wednesday, I was actively working on a mobile app development project. My team and I integrated APIs and tested the user interface. These days also involved many meetings to discuss new ideas and refine functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, we had a seminar on artificial intelligence, where we analyzed examples of neural networks and machine learning applications. I also spent time exploring new libraries and tools for future projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, I decided to take a break from studying and spend time outdoors. On Saturday, I took a walk around the city and visited a technology exhibition, while Sunday was dedicated to reading books and preparing for upcoming exams, readying myself for the challenges of the next week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Week</title>
      <link>https://nvgaforov.github.io/en/post/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nvgaforov.github.io/en/post/22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past week was both busy and productive. On Monday, I began with a lecture on software engineering, where we studied the principles of software architecture design. After classes, I worked on an assignment for object-oriented programming, implementing complex data structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday and Wednesday, I focused on working on a web development project. My team and I integrated new features and tested the interface, which took a lot of time and effort. On Wednesday evening, I attended a data analysis seminar where we discussed machine learning methods and their applications to real-world tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday was dedicated to preparing for an exam on database management systems. I spent time studying complex queries and practicing database creation and optimization. By Friday, I had completed the project and presented it in an internal review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, I decided to relax and have some fun. On Saturday, I went to the gym and had dinner with friends, while Sunday was spent reading academic articles and preparing for the upcoming week to be ready for new academic challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Week</title>
      <link>https://nvgaforov.github.io/en/post/32/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nvgaforov.github.io/en/post/32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past week was quite eventful. Monday began with a lecture on computational systems, where we studied the architecture of modern processors and their optimization. After the lectures, I focused on a lab project in systems programming, where I created my own version of a file system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, I delved into machine learning algorithms during a practical session. We worked on a data classification project, applying different models and evaluating their effectiveness. On Wednesday, I continued improving the project, fine-tuning algorithms and adjusting the models&amp;rsquo; hyperparameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday was dedicated to preparing for a seminar on cryptography. I studied modern encryption methods and their applications, preparing a report for discussion. On Friday, I spent time in a consultation with my professor to clarify some questions that came up during my preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, I decided to take a break from academic work. On Saturday, I went to the movies with friends, and on Sunday, I spent the day reading books about new technologies and planning my next steps in my studies. It was a great way to relax and prepare for the upcoming week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Week</title>
      <link>https://nvgaforov.github.io/en/post/42/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nvgaforov.github.io/en/post/42/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past week was full of activity and interesting tasks. On Monday, I attended a lecture on databases, where we delved into the topic of indexing and query optimization. After the lecture, I spent time working on a lab assignment related to creating and managing relational databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, I worked on a game development project. My team and I were programming the game engine and testing new mechanics. Throughout the week, I also attended a practical session on network programming, where we studied network configuration and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, I focused on preparing for the exam on operating systems. I reviewed key topics such as memory management and multitasking. On Friday, I finished working on a software development project and presented it during a defense at the university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the weekend productively. On Saturday, I met up with friends for a walk around the city and enjoyed the fresh air. On Sunday, I dedicated time to self-education, studying new trends in artificial intelligence and watching educational videos. It was a great end to the week and a preparation for the new challenges ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Week</title>
      <link>https://nvgaforov.github.io/en/post/51/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nvgaforov.github.io/en/post/51/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week, as a computer science student, I spent my time quite productively. Monday started with a lecture on mobile app development, where we studied the basics of working with APIs and integrating external services. After class, I immersed myself in a project to create a simple mobile app, adding new features and fixing bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday and Wednesday, I worked on research related to machine learning. My team and I analyzed datasets, trained models, and compared their results. On Wednesday evening, I attended a seminar on optimization algorithms, where I learned about new methods to improve computational processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday was dedicated to preparing for an exam on algorithm theory. I reviewed the main sorting and search algorithms, solved practical problems, and tested my knowledge. On Friday, I completed the development of modules for a web programming lab, where we created user interaction interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the weekend, I decided to relax and recharge. On Saturday, I went on a tour of local attractions, and on Sunday, I spent time reading books and planning future projects to be ready for new challenges in the upcoming week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
